

# **Azad Mamiyev**

# Android Developer

azad.mamiyev.1998@gmail.com

**♦** +994519313727 **♦** Baku, Azerbaijan

#### **PROFILE**

An Android Developer with 4 years of experience in developing, designing, and maintaining Android apps in multiple industries such as product tech companies, startups, and consulting agencies. Experienced in delivering features via A/B Testing, building Bitrise pipelines, writing tests, refactoring, and optimizing existing code.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Azercell ∅

Sep 2023 - present Baku, Azerbaijan

• Overseeing the application separation process.

Mobile Platform Developer, Cookpad &

• Migrated a flow of onboarding screens from XML Views to Jetpack Compose.

Aug 2022 - Jul 2023 Bristol, United Kingdom

- Working on building, editing, and optimizing Bitrise pipelines
- Covered features with unit, integration, and E2E tests.
- Assisting iOS Engineers with migration to use generated paths using CreateAPI.
- Exoplayer improvements (Better Buffering, Audio, New Features) by releasing via A/B testing. The wait time for video buffering decreased by 3 times.
- Release manager responsibilities: Releasing updates and monitoring Crashlytics.

Android Developer, ByAllMeans &

Aug 2020 - Jul 2022

• Developed chat-related features with reactions.

Prague, Czech Republic

- Actively participated in product management, design & QA team meetings.
- Implemented Google Play Billing Library.
- Maintained the existing project with improvements to user experience.

# **EDUCATION**

**MSc.**, Web & Software Engineering, Czech Technical University in Prague @

Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

• Experienced in genetic algorithms and management information systems.

Prague, Czech Republic

• Well-versed in patterns, user interface design, and networking.

**BSc., Computer Science,** Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry University &

Sep 2015 - Jun 2019

• Gained experience working on group projects.

Baku, Azerbaijan

## **SKILLS**

Kotlin, Java, Swift, Jetpack Compose, Kotlin Flow and Coroutines, RxJava, Rest API, GraphQL, OkHttp, OpenAPI, Retrofit, Jetpack Libraries, Firebase Tools, SqlDelight, Koin, Dagger Hilt, Timber, jUnit, Espresso, Kaspresso, Mockito

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

**Habitube,** Movie Library App ⊘

- Successfully facilitated seamless migration from legacy technologies (Java, RxJava, XML Views) to modern development technologies (Kotlin, Coroutines, Compose) for end users.
- Designed elegant and user-friendly interfaces using Figma.

### **LANGUAGES**

**English** Azerbaijani Russian **Turkish** Fluent Native Native Limited